<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>ein_teil_von_mir</title>
		<description>["data mining", "R", "machine learning", "python", "and more ..."]</description>
		<link></link>
		<atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Tracking counts along time with Redis</title>
				<description>
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
				<link>/2015/04/29/redis-time-series-counter/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/2015/04/29/redis-time-series-counter/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>print "Hello World!"</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Hello World!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m Victor and this is my second blog post ever, the first in this new project, which I’ve built using &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; together with &lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; as blog engine. So far I think it’s a great tool. I spent only a few hours installing it on my laptop and customizing the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mattvh.github.io/solar-theme-jekyll/&quot;&gt;Solar Theme&lt;/a&gt;, et voilà! I have finally a blog engine which fits quite good to my needs and the best of all, open source software, no database, no hosting costs and no dealing with the pain of customizing proprietary blog engines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this is the start of a nice and long-lasting blogging story as opposed to my first attempt, which I started about five years ago before moving to Berlin, with the idea of writing about the experiences and adventures I was going to go through in that new stage of my life I was about to start. Sadly, that blog ended having only one post, I could never find simultaneously both enough motivation and free time to write and it simply sunk into oblivion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new project has nothing to do with that first blog as you might notice. Here I will be writing about some of the projects I’ve been working on during the last years and also about the new ones that are still to come. In short, I’m half Software Engineer, half Data Nerd, fluent with Java, Python, PHP, R and some javascript. In the last years I’ve been developing recommendation algorithms and self teaching myself how to become a Data Scientist. Currently still learning about Python scientific stack while having some fun now and then with some Kaggle competitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s still something that links the two blogs, though, I decided to name this blog as the old failed one. The title ‘Ein teil von mir’, which was inspired originally by the text of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UwQfDTkLmfA&quot;&gt;Berlin techno anthem&lt;/a&gt;, means ‘A part of me’. And that’s the goal I had in mind when I decided to start the two projects, sharing a part of me with the world. I hope the knowledge I share here is helpful for some of you or at least you enjoy reading and learning some stuff. I am open to constructive critics and feedback, I will try to integrate disqus in the next weeks to provide a way of interaction with my readers. I will keep you informed about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot; data-lang=&quot;python&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_bye&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;str&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;):&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;See you soon &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;%s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;!&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;str&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hello&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;World&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &amp;#39;See you soon World!&amp;#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
				<link>/2015/04/28/hello-world/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/2015/04/28/hello-world/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
